<X-word-ms ms=280,339,180,219,219,179,160,219,280,339,120,239,540 index=1 character_ranges=0-6,7-12,13-15,16-21,22-24,25-29,30-31,32-36,37-41,42-44,45-48,49-57,58-69>Jeffrey Sachs is about to give a talk here in the European Parliament.
<X-word-ms ms=200,279,700,479,620,120,280 index=2 character_ranges=0-3,4-7,8-15,16-25,26-28,29-32,33-37>What was Putin's intention in the war?
<X-word-ms ms=540,520,619,500,259,320,320 index=3 character_ranges=0-2,3-6,7-17,18-24,25-32,33-38,39-44>Not the propaganda that's written about this,
<X-word-ms ms=140,199,179,480,199,100,159,120,160,219,280,519 index=4 character_ranges=0-2,3-7,8-12,13-19,20-23,24-26,27-30,31-36,37-39,40-44,45-49,50-58>oh, that they failed and he was going to take over Ukraine.
<X-word-ms ms=559,480,359,240,400,1320,280,259,420 index=5 character_ranges=0-2,3-7,8-11,12-14,15-19,20-28,29-33,34-36,37-42>The idea was to keep NATO—and what is NATO?
<X-word-ms ms=259,100,219,580,699,480,859,419 index=6 character_ranges=0-3,4-7,8-14,15-21,22-25,26-28,29-37,38-45>It's the United States off of Russia's border.
<X-word-ms ms=420,439,260,339,440,199,300,399,500,280,1000 index=7 character_ranges=0-1,2-7,8-10,11-15,16-20,21-24,25-31,32-37,38-43,44-46,47-51>No more, no less when the Soviet Union ended in 1991
<X-word-ms ms=820,339,479,380,379,480,339,239,260,280,279,400,599 index=8 character_ranges=0-2,3-5,6-15,16-19,20-24,25-29,30-34,35-39,40-43,44-48,49-52,53-57,58-67>and an agreement was made that NATO will not move one inch eastward.
<X-word-ms ms=399,339,440,379,760 index=9 character_ranges=0-3,4-8,9-17,18-23,24-29>Now, what happened after 1991?
<X-word-ms ms=479,179,520,579,520,179,159,260,459,360 index=10 character_ranges=0-2,3-9,10-16,17-24,25-30,31-36,37-39,40-42,43-46,47-49>The United States decided there would be no end to
<X-word-ms ms=559,600,420,320,359,240,320,339,280,659,539,740 index=11 character_ranges=0-7,8-19,20-22,23-27,28-31,32-35,36-44,45-48,49-54,55-63,64-66,67-71>eastward enlargement of NATO And the decision was taken formally in 1994
<X-word-ms ms=940,579,379,359,400,359,519,620 index=12 character_ranges=0-3,4-13,14-21,22-28,29-32,33-35,36-40,41-51>when President Clinton signed off on NATO enlargment
<X-word-ms ms=280,959,200,320,339,480,420 index=13 character_ranges=0-2,3-6,7-10,11-15,16-23,24-28,29-36>all the way from Ukraine into Georgia
<X-word-ms ms=399,199,280,679,179,120,159,440 index=14 character_ranges=0-1,2-5,6-10,11-22,23-25,26-29,30-34,35-42>So the NATO enlargement as you know started
<X-word-ms ms=240,0,0,200,460,299,519,520,500,280 index=15 character_ranges=0-1,2-5,6-14,15-18,19-25,26-29,30-39,40-47,48-53,54-56>in the Republic and Russia was extremely unhappy about it
<X-word-ms ms=299,380,200,479,299,500,380 index=16 character_ranges=0-2,3-8,9-13,14-23,24-29,30-33,34-38>but these were countries still far from
<X-word-ms ms=380,320,259,140,79,520,239,220,679,359 index=17 character_ranges=0-2,3-10,11-14,15-17,18-22,23-28,29-31,32-36,37-48,49-53>The border. So, so next round of NATO enlargement came
In 2004
<X-word-ms ms=380,119,200,560,239 index=19 character_ranges=0-3,4-7,8-13,14-20,21-27>with the three Baltic states
Romania Bulgaria Slovenia
<X-word-ms ms=340,659,299,159,240 index=21 character_ranges=0-2,3-11,12-14,15-19,20-25>And Slovakia At this point
<X-word-ms ms=319,380,379,560,619 index=22 character_ranges=0-5,6-9,10-16,17-21,22-27>Russia Was pretty damn upset
So as everybody recalls
<X-word-ms ms=80,780,599,400,299 index=24 character_ranges=0-1,2-6,7-16,17-22,23-27>In 2007 President Putin said
Stop Enough And
<X-word-ms ms=180,280,239,200,259 index=26 character_ranges=0-1,2-8,9-13,14-18,19-24>Of course what that meant
<X-word-ms ms=260,460,799,599,640,140,560,280 index=27 character_ranges=0-2,3-7,8-14,15-21,22-28,29-33,34-42,43-49>was 2008 United States jammed down Europe's throat
<X-word-ms ms=899,280,260,299,480,140,179 index=28 character_ranges=0-10,11-13,14-18,19-21,22-29,30-33,34-41>Enlargement of NATO to Ukraine and Georgia
<X-word-ms ms=390,299,459,460,539,680 index=29 character_ranges=0-3,4-6,7-12,13-15,16-23,24-30>This is right up against Russia
And Russia protested
Because if Russia decided
<X-word-ms ms=340,239,280,519,500,260,99,240,399 index=32 character_ranges=0-1,2-6,7-8,9-17,18-22,23-25,26-29,30-33,34-40>To have a military base on the Rio Grande
Or The Canadian border
<X-word-ms ms=379,260,219,200,519,359,260 index=34 character_ranges=0-2,3-7,8-13,14-20,21-27,28-33,34-37>Not only would United States freak out
<X-word-ms ms=259,120,340,319,320,319,359 index=35 character_ranges=0-3,4-8,9-12,13-19,20-25,26-28,29-36>We'd Have war within about 10 minutes
A month later
<X-word-ms ms=240,379,319,340,420 index=37 character_ranges=0-2,3-8,9-12,13-17,18-22>War broke Out That gets
Georgia destroyed
Starting in 2010
<X-word-ms ms=500,439,160,419,280,540 index=40 character_ranges=0-1,2-5,6-8,9-14,15-22,23-30>US put In Aegis missile systems
Poland Then Romania
<X-word-ms ms=390,420,700,280,280 index=42 character_ranges=0-2,3-9,10-17,18-22,23-27>And Russia doesn't like that
In 2010
Viktor Yanukovych
<X-word-ms ms=340,420,540,219,599,359,640 index=45 character_ranges=0-2,3-10,11-13,14-17,18-26,27-29,30-40>Was elected On the platform of neutrality
Russia had
No Territorial
Interests Or designs
in Ukraine
At all What
Russia was negotiating
<X-word-ms ms=439,159,540,659,419 index=52 character_ranges=0-2,3-4,5-7,8-12,13-18>Was a 25-year lease
For Sevastopol
Naval base That's it
Not for Crimea
Not For The Donbas
Nothing In 2014
US Worked Actively
To Overthrow Yannikovich
Everybody Knows
<X-word-ms ms=219,219,379,180,379 index=61 character_ranges=0-2,3-8,9-13,14-16,17-19>The phone call By My
Columbia University
Colleague Victoria Newland
And U.S
Ambassador Peter Piat
Listen To It Is
Fascinating I Don't
<X-word-ms ms=219,259,180,159,200 index=68 character_ranges=0-4,5-11,12-18,19-21,22-26>Think Cleats Should Go Into
<X-word-ms ms=299,360,99,120,120,539 index=69 character_ranges=0-9,10-11,12-17,18-23,24-28,29-38>Government I Don't Think It's Necessary
Good Idea I
<X-word-ms ms=259,379,159,120,260 index=71 character_ranges=0-4,5-11,12-14,15-18,19-22>Think Yachts Is The guy
<X-word-ms ms=279,40,299,260,340 index=72 character_ranges=0-2,3-6,7-10,11-19,20-30>Who Has Got Economic Experience
The Governance Experience
You Know Fuck
EU No Exactly
And We Have
Do Something To Make
<X-word-ms ms=39,340,259,199,400 index=78 character_ranges=0-0,1-4,5-9,10-13,14-20>A You Don' Get Better
Evidence Then
Came Minsk
And Especially Mints
Too It Said
There Should Be Autonomy
For The Russian
Speaking Regions
<X-word-ms ms=219,99,259,240,319 index=86 character_ranges=0-1,2-5,6-10,11-13,14-21>In The East Of Ukraine
It Was Supported
Unanimously By
the UN Security Council
The United States
And You Crane
Decided It Was Not
To be Enforced There
Were Many
Thousands Of Deaths
<X-word-ms ms=140,159,340,279,380 index=96 character_ranges=0-1,2-5,6-14,15-17,18-25>in The Shelling by Ukraine
Donbas and
<X-word-ms ms=279,180,80,400,179 index=98 character_ranges=0-2,3-5,6-9,10-16,17-19>One of The Issues On
The Table In December
2021 January
2022 Was Does
The United States Claim
<X-word-ms ms=219,240,219,139,400 index=103 character_ranges=0-2,3-8,9-11,12-15,16-23>the Right To Put Missile
Systems In Ukraine And
Blinken Told
Lavrov in
January 20
22 The United
States Reserves
<X-word-ms ms=159,219,180,180,299 index=110 character_ranges=0-2,3-8,9-11,12-15,16-23>The right to put missile
systems wherever it
wants So The
War Started What
was Putin's
Intention In
The war It Was
To Force Zelensky
To Negotiate
Neutrality and
That Happened Within
Seven Days
Of The Start
of This The Invasion
Ukraine Walked
Away Unilaterally From
A Near Agreement
Why Because
the United States
Told Them To
The Idea Was
That There
Would Be Ukraine
Romania Bulgaria
Turkey
And Georgia
that would Deprive
Russia Of
Any International Status
By Blocking
The Black Sea
and The American
Senators Who Are
As Nasty
And Cynical And
Corrupt As Imaginable
Say This Is Wonderful
Expenditure Of
Our Money Because No
Americans Are Dying
It's The Pure Proxy
War and Since
the U.S Talked
The Negotiators Away
From Table About A
Million Ukrainians
Have Died Or Been
Severely Wounded